To get us ready to look at the risk factor model,
在学习风险因子模型之前
let's review the factor model of returns.
我们先回顾下收益率因子模型
Note that some of this may look familiar from an earlier lesson, which is great.
注意 某些知识之前已经讲过 这是好事
Our team is really excited about what you'll be able
我们的团队非常激动和期待
to do by the time you get to this next project.
你将在下个实战项目中完成的操作
But we also recognize that it's
但是我们也知道
a pretty steep climb to reach the top of the mountain of knowledge.
爬上知识巅峰的道路很曲折
So, we're trying to guide you up the mountain as gently as possible.
所以我们希望尽可能平缓地带领你攀登
Let's begin by looking at a factor model of return.
首先看看收益率因子模型
For a single stock and a single factor,
对于单个股票和单个因子
the return of a stock can be modeled as the sum of
股票的收益率可以表示成两部分的和
two parts: the factor contribution to return plus the specific return.
因子对收益率的贡献加上特有收益率
The contribution of the factors is also called the common return.
因子的贡献也称为公共收益率
The common return is defined as the stock's exposure to that factor times the rate of
公共收益率等于股票对该因子的暴露度
return of the factor is the part of
乘以因子的收益率
the stock's return that can be explained by the factor.
它属于因子能够解释的股票收益率
The stock's exposure to the factor has a couple commonly used names: factor exposure,
股票对因子的暴露度有几个常见名称
factor loading, factor sensitivity, or factor beta.
包括因子暴露度 因子载荷 因子敏感度和因子 beta
We'll refer to this as the factor exposure.
我们将称之为因子暴露度
The rate of return of the factor is the percent change of a particular factor.
因子的收益率是指特定因子的百分比变化
We'll call this the factor return.
我们称之为因子收益率
An example of a factor that we've seen before is the market return,
我们之前见过的市场收益率就属于因子
as approximated by an index such as the S&amp;P 500.
它等于 S&amp;P 500 等指数的近似值
The other contributor to the stock return is the specific return
股票收益率的其他贡献者是特有收益率
which is the return of the stock that is not explained by the factors in the model.
即模型中因子无法解释的股票收益率
This may also be referred to as the idiosyncratic return or idiosyncratic shock.
也称为特质收益率或特质冲击
We'll call this the specific return.
我们将称之为特有收益率
So, to summarize, the stock return equals
总结下 股票收益率等于
the factor exposure times the factor return plus the specific return.
因子暴露度乘以因子收益率加上特有收益率
A model can have multiple factors contributing to the return of the stock.
模型中可能有多个因子对股票收益率有贡献
So, for instance, the return can be modeled as the contribution
例如 收益率可能等于
of one factor plus the contribution of a second factor.
一个因子的贡献加上第二个因子的贡献
As before, the specific return represents the part of
和之前一样 特有收益率表示
the stock return that isn't explained by the chosen factors.
所选因子无法解释的股票收益率
In general, we can choose any number of factors in order to model stock's return.
通常 我们在创建股票收益率模型时 可以选择任意数量的因子
We can refer to this as a multi-factor model of returns.
称之为多因子收益率模型
Cool. So, that was how we model the return of a single stock,
好的我们就是通过这种方式对单支股票的收益率进行建模
but as you may guess,
但是你可能猜到了
we're going to be more interested in a portfolio of stocks.
我们对股票投资组合更感兴趣
Let's see how factor models describe a portfolio of stocks next.
接下来我们将学习如何用因子模型描述投资组合